You're listening to TIP. In today's episode, I'm joined by my friends and fellow value investors to buy Skylile and Hyramatandra for another round of dare I say, unloved stock pitches. We kick things off with Hari's pitch of Meta. The business is firing on own cylinders, yet the market has been selling off the stock and we discuss whether investors should be worried about rising capital expenditures and whether Meta's competitive advances lies in its AR models.
or in its unmatched distribution and data. Now Tobias walks us through booking holdings, one of the world's leading travel platforms. We debate whether AI systems could eventually replace travel aggregators altogether, or if booking relationships, networking effects, and position in the travel ecosystem makes it more durable than investors currently believe. And finally, I pits the most unloved stock of them all, Adobe. The stock is trading near multi-year lows as the mug wears about
Yes, you guessed it, the threat of AI. And the reason the departure of the CEO and CFO has not made the narrative more compelling. So we discussed switching costs and whether Adobe's biggest challenge is technological disruption or something completely different in a rapid changing environment. As always, there's plenty to disagree with, plenty to think about, and a few investing lessons along the way. So without further ado, let's jump right in.
We have interviewed the world's best investors, studied deeply the principles of value investing and uncovered many compelling investment opportunities. We focus on understanding businesses and intrinsic value, investing accordingly and sharing everything we learn with you. This show is not investment advice. It's intended for informational and entertainment purposes only. All opinions expressed by hosts and guests are solely their own and they may have investments in the securities discussed.
Now for your host, Stig Brodersen. Welcome to the Investors Podcast. I'm your host, Stig Brodersen. And today, as always, throughout these mastermind discussions, I'm here with Hari and Toby. Jens, how are you today? I'm well, Stig. Good to see you. Good to see you, Hari. Hey, Stig and Toby. Hello from India. Good to see you both. Take it away. Awesome. My pick for this time is Meta. When I was looking at the recent
shuffle in the market. I see many names falling down and Meta was one of them. Its share price from its peak has fallen down by 20%. And when I looked at the company, the business is pretty strong. They're one of the two best advertising machines ever built. In fact, they are on track to beat Google in terms of ad revenues. They're forecasted ad revenue for 2020
6 is $243 billion which would be $3 billion more than Google's and they're growing their operating margin is very healthy at 41% with a 46 billion free cash flow in 2025 a 30% net margin their revenue has been growing pretty healthily for last five years with a 18.5% CAGR revenue growth
So what's the problem? And the problem is something that is not new to Meta. They are very bold and very swift in making serious bets and they put serious dollars behind those bets. Metaverse was one of them which market got spooked when they didn't see much returns and they saw it as a money pit. VR Labs was another one.
the reality labs and this time what has booked market is their investments of their projected capex especially of 135 billion dollars into building their data centers and infrastructure for their AI. Their big back that they're making their first LLM Lama was not a big success but recently their super intelligence group came up with their latest model.
which has performed really well compared to other foundational models out in the market, which gives me confidence that one, they have the ability to come up with a good model. Two, as we are seeing that models are pretty much getting commoditized, that means the incremental difference between models is kind of getting saturated. Distribution becomes more
advantages. It's the distribution that matters whether it is GROC with XAI, Gemini of Google, Meta has a solid distribution. The second thing with Google and Meta is they have a lot of use for AI to make their products better, their ad targeting better. So they don't have to look for subscription model immediately. They can actually improve their
profitability, their revenue streams for their existing products with AI, but they're also trying to diversify into subscription. They are also looking into cloud business, but I'm not going to be accounting for those because those are still kind of, you know, things in on the drawing board. So my base case is that their network effects, the mode that comes out of it, the
ability to use AI as an engine for their ad business, their pricing power, and then the discipline they have exhibited wherein Zuck said in 2023, it's a year of efficiency. Even in 2026, they have reduced their workforce. So they're kind of not going off-hinge in terms of spending. So I'm hoping that that will continue. So my base case is based on these
they're able to recover their FCF margin and also the growth stabilizes without any re-rating of the price to earnings, I see a 46% upside from here. If they really hit the ball out of the park with their AI monetization, then it can be much more. So that's kind of my case for Meta and I look forward to your feedback. Toby and stick. Thank you.
Good one Harry. I like meta. I think it's a good pick. I agree with everything that you said. I think it's a absolutely world-class business. One of the very unusual ones that still found the lead where Zuck is really fully engaged and he's young and he's done a really good job. So might be one of the best managers in the business at the moment. Absolutely gushes free cash flow and just grows ridiculously fast. You've got that.
optionality that they figure out AI. It doesn't seem like they're a loser in that race. They're competitive at least, even if they're not at the forefront. Because as you say, the model seemed to be commoditized over time. And so you don't necessarily need to have the best model. You just need to have a model that's competitive with the other ones. I think for meta, the big issue is I think it's the same one for all of them that they've all got this massive capex to chase this opportunity.
It's hard to say whether we're looking back on this in five years time will be like, oh, silly. Of course, these guys were all going to figure out how to monetize this thing and that was going to be or they all sort of tried to spend all the money at the same time and they all caused each other to overspend and the underlying kind of trajectory of the growth of these businesses was going to be sustained anyway. And so they've just had this period where they've really overspent on
CapEx and it's not clear how they're going to generate the revenue out of that CapEx over and above what they're already doing. And I think that's what the market sees. I think that's why it's probably reasonable value on what it's already done. But there's some discount for the uncertainty of their ability to execute on AI. It's a hard question to answer. I think that it's such a high quality business that really your risk is not that you're down 50% on a position like this.
I think the risk is just that for a period of time, and I don't know how long this is, but it could be five years, they just earn on what they've invested and the multiples come down as a result. And they just have like a, I don't know how long, but a period of time while they work through the sort of CAPEX spending and stud earning enough on that investment. And at the same time, the problem with the spend on this stuff is that the chip's age
Faster than infrastructure has in the past like it's not like a railway or fiber optic cable which sits in the ground for a really long period of time and you just wait for demand to catch up. I think this the chips age a little bit faster than that. Yeah, you're right. Actually it needs some faith. So, Hari again, I really appreciate it. It's such an interesting time that we're in and I have to talk a bit about AI. I can't help myself.
Let me ask you a question. And the reason I want to probably want to preference this by saying that, you know, we created a model here on TAP of Meta and we came up with a valuation of 775 at the time recording is trading at 600 and change. But of course, whenever you do that, you have different scenarios and you assign different probabilities and then you look back and you're like, oh, like to talk this point, this happened, wasn't that obvious that it would happen and
I don't know. Right now, I'm talking about the future. I don't think anything is obvious in terms of what's going to happen with AI. Whenever we see the result, we think it's obvious. But then, again, you sign the probabilities to what you think is going to happen. But one of the things that I can't help but think about for many of the stocks in my own portfolio is what happens if computing becomes free or essentially free. I know it sounds a bit odd to have the framework. It's a bit like
you had a lot of companies, you had this thesis for the longest time, what happens if we figured out how to make abundant energy for example, like and then all energy is free, then we have clean drinking water for the entire world because it's so much energy, but now it's free. So it might sound very theoretical. At the same time, you also see what's going on right now and you see how much cheaper everything becomes in terms of, for example,
inference, but then at the same time, you also need that much more. And so you have these two things that are trying to counter with each other. But anyways, I wanted to ask this is going to be a very long question. As you can tell, like what happens if computing, I'm definitely going to use the wrong word here. I hope you know, you see, we're going to computing AI, whatever you call it, whatever you need to do, if that becomes free or cheap. And so let me talk a bit more about the framework here because meta has so much data.
that what happens if they can utilize all that data and collect all of that data and it's essentially free for them to compute. And then you can basically go to Meta and say, here's $100,000 for my campaign. This is my objective. Figure it out. And then Meta is going to figure it out because computing is free. Or is that not the way to think about it at all because
meta doesn't have that type of advantage if computer becomes free because then everyone can collect the same amount of data because everything is possible and That's going to be a framework. I know it sounds like a bit of an odd question But I think you sort of like break it down from there. So let me throw a bag over to you, Hari Yeah, actually great questions taken that's kind of the million dollar question now All of these guys are facing if you look at AI in general, I think it is constrained by power
It is constrained by real estate or space because you got to build the data center somewhere. And it is constrained by chips or the GPUs currently. Of course, now there are competition from Google and Amazon and others with TPUs. And there are specialized chips for inference versus training coming in and then the models are also being optimized. So the arc is towards that. So right now we are
heavily constrained by chips today. But as you mentioned, the arc is towards a place where we might no longer be constrained by that by a factor of one competition catching up. So supply coming into the market to the model themselves becoming more efficient. And there is a lot of papers now being published on that area. And I'm following the that where so far it was all about features in the model, if you will.
Now it's all about how to optimize the model for energy, for cost. In fact, Google Flash, Gemini Flash, recently in their Google I.O., they talked about how if you use Flash, you will save billions of dollars because it's much more efficient. So that conversations have already started. So I think with that arc continuing, Facebook has the advantage that it has the world garden. Not everybody has access to what the data Facebook has.
and it can leverage that data whether it is for better at targeting or for suggesting products to its customers or even coming up with new features and product and subscription model for its customers based on the treasure trove data they have. So that can prove to be an advantage for Facebook because their cost of delivering AI goes down as chips gets commoditized or model becomes more efficient.
Now they have the advantage of data. Thank you so much, Hari. Toby, you are up with your pick. Mine is also a AI impacted name. I like booking. Booking.com. If you're in the States, you'll see any ads, rate ads. Booking.com really sticks in the mind. It's a big company. It's much bigger than I usually pitch. And it's more expensive than I usually pitch.
But I think it's interesting because it is so dominant and I think it's one of the unusual chance that you get to buy one of these companies cheaply. Just so for folks who don't know, booking is a business that allows you to book travel. They have booking.com price line, which has been a great business forever. I go to, I don't know particularly well, but Kayak is also a name that folks will recognize and open table. Over time, there's
secular growth and travel as people become more wealthy, they tend to travel more and they're able to control the experience. They're able to upsell and control various parts of the experience. They have a business model that doesn't. So through 2020, some of the other sites in the net to compete with booking, they buy rooms up front. They would court when the rooms weren't taken. Booking.com doesn't do that. They don't buy their rooms up front, so they're very capitalite.
They don't only employing assets they just hook people up the big risk to booking is that folks think that they can somehow they will figure out how to get AI to control you just type into your AI that you want to book a trip somewhere and the AI will will do that for you without you having to interact with any of these sites and it will either do it directly and therefore cut out booking dot com.
So booking.com their thesis though is that that doesn't happen. So they're not disintermediated because there is a large database of all these sites and their relationships that needs to be maintained. It's not a simple matter of just calling them and paying them. They have these specialized relationships. And so in order for chat GPT or Claude or one of the other LLMs to access these travel agents, I'll need to go through booking.com.
in order to do it. I don't know what the likelihood of that actually happening is, but that's their thesis. They think that they won't be disintermediated, that they will continue to be part of that acquisition, that purchase journey. The rest of the business is very well managed. Capital allocation is excellent. As a result, it tends to be very high return on invested capital. It's grown very steadily for years and years and has all the things that make it a great business, very asset-like, great sort of
network once people get used to the site this is switching costs lots of free cash flow to the competitive advantages i think are. The risks to booking travel is still somewhat cyclical with the economy goes through a week a period then folks just tend to travel less and because of the way that booking is priced really is priced.
Assuming some future growth or assuming that it continues to grow into the future, somewhat like it has in the past, if that revenue growth slows down, that's the return we would likely expect. I think the most likely outcome is that travel just generally grows as it has historically. I like companies that buy back stock at opportunity times and I think that they're doing a good job buying back here. The bull case is that
AI helps them and they become this sort of channel for all of these other LMS and they just continue to grow. They interconnect with them seamlessly. You don't even know that it happens and so they do a lot better than they have historically. You can handicap the bull and the bear and maybe they cancel out and so the base case is the most likely which is just that they keep on sort of muddling along.
I think that booking is a reasonable risk adjusted bet at these levels because it's a little bit depressed with the tier and LLMs, but there's a reasonable chance that they are beneficiaries of that. Very interesting pick, Toby. And I think there are so many. Suddenly the market has become interesting now with the AI scare. One question I have is, I agree with you, the relationships booking has the channels they have maintained.
is definitely a mode for them even if I'm going through say chat gpt or anthropic cloud client and booking becomes like a headless and provides an API it might go in background but I'm still querying booking through chat gpt or llm as so booking can be a plugin to chat gpt so that's kind of the case where it's still there it's not disrupted however
In the longer term, so in the short term, it's not a problem but in the longer term They're gradually losing the mind share and they're also losing the real estate in the sense that Right now folks land on booking Website and they can cross sell to them. You can promote you can show advertisements and then you know people discover things as they are on the site
So those are some of the opportunities they might lose in the long term if they just become a plug-in for Claude or OpenA. It's certainly sold off over the last sort of six months after being a pretty consistent compounder for a very long period of time. I do think that the valuation is a little bit ahead of itself, but I think the valuation has, it is at a reasonable discount now or if it loses that mind share then
That's the bear case. That's the risk. So I think it's a great question. I don't have a great answer, but I think that that is really the reason why trades were it does. Let's take a quick break and hear from today's sponsors. Curious about online trading but haven't taken the first step yet? You're not alone. And Plus 500 futures is a great place to start. The futures markets are moving fast and with Plus 500 you can explore popular assets like oil, gold, S&P 500, Bitcoin and more.
From crypto to commodities, there's always something happening. The platform is super easy to use so you can trade on the go right from your phone. You can get started with just $100 and jump into the action. See something interesting? Once your account is open, you can trade it in just a couple of clicks. And if you're not quite ready yet, you can practice with a free demo account. No risk, no pressure. With 20 years of experience, plus 500 makes trading more accessible than ever,
Check it out at plus500.com. Trading and futures involves risks of loss and is not suitable for everyone. Not all applicants will qualify. Plus 500. It's trading with a plus. They say every day your business is late to AI. You fall two days behind in the competition. They're only moving faster. Fortunately, there's NetSuite next. You probably already know NetSuite, the AI-powered business suite that securely connects all your data
financials, inventory, commerce, HR and CRM all in one source of truth trusted by over 43,000 customers. NetSuite next is the next huge leap because now AI is built into everything you do. It surfaces custom insights throughout your day. AI agents work alongside you on the routine stuff. And anytime you've got a question about anything, you just ask like you're talking to a colleague and I use it and really I think you should too.
For the first time ever, you can try NetSuite Next for free. If your revenue is at least in the seven figures, go to netsuite.ai slash tip. Built for every industry, ready for every boardroom, netsuite.ai slash tip. As investors, we spend all day studying great businesses, but some of the best returns come from building one yourself. If you've been sitting out a business idea, Shopify makes it easy to actually make it happen.
Everything you need to start selling is included and ready from day one. Take the moment your first customer is ready to pay. Shopify Checkout helps more of them finish the purchase. And when they come back, their details are already saved. One tap and they're done. And because Shopify handles the setup and the checkout, you get more time to focus on what actually grows the business, plus the tools to do it.
If I were starting a business, I would absolutely use Shopify myself. It powers millions of businesses worldwide, from names like Mattel and Gymshark to founders just getting started at Shopify.com slash TIP. With Shopify, nothing stands between your idea and a real business. So go make it one. Start your free trial at Shopify.com slash TIP.
Start your free trial at Shopify.com slash TIP. All right. Back to the show. I really like your pick, Toby. I always like your picks and this one is no different. Booking has been on my radar for years now. And I can't really figure out now that it's been selling off like if not the time because I do feel like there is a reason why it's selling off. And I know this is very anecdotal, but please take it for what it is. But
You know, I just came back from a wonderful trip to Paris, my wife, and I've seen how we increasingly have started to use LLMs. And like this one probably because it was his recent last week was the one we've used it the most. And it's so incredibly helpful in so many ways. You talked before about all the things that was working behind the scenes that super, super important and that just needs to be done.
And so I'm sort of like using that as a micro custom for it's probably just me who are the ignorant travel like I don't know why it's so difficult that you can't make it through an LM like why can't I tell an LM book me a hotel in Paris throughout this criteria and then I probably need to give a final sign off and then I don't need booking.com at all. I think Harry is absolutely right that there are some wonderful things that something like booking.com can do. For example, you know, you can explore, you can do that different ways.
But I guess I'm not sure if you need intermediary like booking.com if you're already doing it through an LLM that knows you better and would give you like one of the challenges I have a booking.com and I've used it multiple times is that I kind of feel that there are too many options. It's almost like going on Netflix sometimes. And so I'm like, if my LLM of choice is really knows me better than than than anyone, I would probably like to put in different criteria.
Or perhaps I don't even want to put in different criteria because it already knows me. And then these are the three, five choices. And then I'm going to click that one. And so I also think it goes to to Harris point about like, are they going to lose mind share? Perhaps I can probably see a case where it allows because they're so expensive to run, they would need like the booking.coms, their advertising dollar, you know, I think it's well known by now that booking.com is one of the biggest spenders on Google. And I can see you're sort of like why you want to build your big
your business model up around that because the travel is such an obvious thing to use elements for. And so that's a way to monetize it. Right now, they can just raise money without making any money. So perhaps they're saying, no, we just we're basically cutting out the middleman. We don't care about advertising. We're just providing the best possible service. And again, this might be my own travel habits. I would love if I could go to chat dbt or Gemini or whatnot and not go through booking calm. That brings me absolutely no.
pleasure but perhaps I'm just a very anxious traveler. So anyways, those were a few thoughts. Then we said back to you Toby. I think those are good thoughts and I think that is the real risk. We're in this transitional period where we don't really know how everybody's going to interact with all of these businesses and because booking.com is an aggregator, it's entirely possible it is disintermediated by the LLMs.
The only thing I would say is that that has always been the risk, but the book you meant for most of booking.com's history was Google that Google was going to do exactly that, that you could just search. And Google has tried to do that. You can search flights and so on on Google and book all the way through with the carrier. And that's disintermitted booking.com. But booking.com has continued to be as continued to grow and the lion show that despite the fact that Google has been out there.
But again, as Harry mentioned, does that impact their mind share and their ability to charge? I think that's a good question. But I still think that you get, this is not priced for perfection. I think that you're getting a little bit of a discount. And I guess the question is whether the discount is enough for that risk. But I think that there is, if you assume that things go back to normal, it doesn't continue to earn what it has in the past, but maybe it muddles along a little bit below that.
going to too many problems here at the current valuation. So, a way of thinking of this is if booking.com disappeared tomorrow, who would notice it first? Would it be travelers or other hotels? And that's a bit of a probably a bit of a rhetorical question. But I see why booking.com has such a strong foothold, especially here in Europe. We don't have as many brand new chains as you do in the States, for example. So there are a lot of independent hotels. They don't have a lot of rooms and they're very much dependent on the booking.coms of the world.
One of the things that we talked about here before we hit record, because I'm also going to talk about a company where the management is saying AI is going to be a tailwind, not a headwind. But I dare everyone to see if they can find a CEO of a public company who was not saying that AI is definitely not going to disrupt them, but it's going to be a tailwind. Anyways, one of the ways that I like to think about this is, can it replace the entire value chain?
That was also why I was getting at here with hard before where I was saying, okay, when if when and how would it look like if I went to mid and said, here's $100,000 run my campaign. This is what I want to achieve. And then they will figure it out the rest and create the ad and cause like whatever. I probably would like some kind of control, but even so I want to see more money coming in and get a report on that the money I'm putting out and the more automated can be the better.
Of course, it's going to take a long time before AI can like change the sync in my house. But how long is it going to take before I can do something that's completely digital? And so one of the things that I was quite impressed by and have been because I've been using a lot of them here for, well, I'm going to say for the longest time, but having existed for the longest time. But just something like you see what kind of tasks you can do whenever you're traveling and how helpful it is in terms of planning, whatever.
I don't know. Whenever I look at what booking.com is doing, I wonder if it can do the entire value chain and how long it's going to take. And I'm not again, I kind of sound overly various. I've been looking at this wonderful company for the longest time. I think it's a very, very strong company. So please don't get me wrong. I think it might be a helpful framework in terms of seeing when is this going to be disrupted and how is it going to be disrupted? Because if it can only take a small part of the value chain and then do it much, much better,
Then it could be a tailwind. So anyways, just a few thoughts that came off way too much bearish than I wanted it to sound like. I think they're off about 30% from their high on a sort of DCF basis. I think you can get to about $220. I think it's worth about it's trading at about 167 today. So the question is, is that enough of a discount for those risks? And that 220 is based on sort of historical growth, right?
They've bought back a significant amount of stock over the last 12 months as they've traded down. I think it might be one of the bellweather stocks that we watch and tells us how the LLMs are impacting other businesses. It's an interesting time in the market for us. It definitely is. All right. Thank you so much. Toby, now it's time for you to bash my pick. My pick is Adobe.
And if anyone is unfamiliar with Adobe, it's a software company. They're known for Photoshop particular. But now, you know, they have a ton of different apps you typically use if you're a designer, creative person. They also have something called digital experience that's more about analytics. But my pick is Adobe, I guess that's what I'm trying to say. Market cap, roughly $100 billion. And it has been growing double digits for the longest time.
And it's not only trading at a 52 week low or near that, but near a seven year low. And of course, I should have said that it traded at 224 not too long ago at the time recording. It's 270. So it had a small bump. But the market like all software or SaaS companies these days just is just unloved because at first glance, there is a lot to love.
96% of the $23 billion in revenue comes from subscription revenue. That is exactly what you want to see diversified base of more than 41 million paying users. And I mean, if I had pitched this just a few years ago before the era of the LMS, we'll be all over it. But of course, you could also see that in evaluation because everyone was at some point in time trying to make their software business into, you know,
software as a service for the subscription and Adobe has really been one of the companies that that men's do that successfully. You know, back in the day, you would not use it in the cloud. You would use it, you would get a CD and then you would install it. And then some of the younger listeners are probably saying, Hey, dude, grandpa, what's that? What's the CD to which I'm going to say it's a more modern version of a Flubby Disc. And so
Of course, that's my way of saying that I'm super old. But it's also my way of saying that Adobe IPO 1986 and it's really been the industry standard more or less ever since. Many people don't think about a PDF whenever they use that today. That's a standard you're owned by Adobe. And there is something to be said about whenever you, for example, whenever I'm calling a car or I would visit Toby, I would be Ubering. That's a verb.
And if I'm going to edit a photo, I am not editing a photo. I am photoshopping. And, you know, Adobe saw that a long time ago. Actually, they didn't come up with photoshopped themselves. They acquired the rights to market it from the Noel Brothers. But it's a long time ago. And today, you know, everyone associates very much photoshopped with Adobe. Launched 1990. Let's just continue to take a trip down memory lane.
It was four years before Netscape for your listeners who remember that company. All right. So let's talk a bit about the competitive advantage. The most important mode, I would say, is switching costs. And I was hitting at before, you can think of Adobe as having two segments. They have digital media, it's a 76%.
after business and that's when you have the creative cloud you have the document cloud where that resides and then you have digital experiences that the enterprise. Software business that help companies manage your marketing customer data e-commerce digital content and so on and we all creature of habits and as uninspiring as it sounds inertia is just very good when you think about it in terms of of a business model.
And you also have to consider that people follow incentives. And of course, in this day and age with AI, it seems like it should be a tailwind. You know, shareholders management, that they want the employees of whatever kind of company to embrace AI. For example, to become more productive or to save on costs. Guess what? Most employees do not have the same incentive. They think and perhaps rightly so that any efficiency gains
doesn't really benefit their paycheck. And in worst case, they can lose their own or the co-workers jobs. And so, management and shareholders just are way more excited about embracing AI to cut costs with very often mean salaries. And I would also say that it sounds good on paper, right? But let's look at from the other side, even if we are looking away from the financial incentives and job risk and so on and so forth,
There is a professional pride in knowing how to use Adobe. If you're a designer and you're taught those tools, you've used it for decades, it's really difficult to embrace a new technology where there is a level playing field for, I wouldn't say everyone, but more or less everyone, and certainly someone who is entry level who might be making a third of what you're making. You don't really have that incentive to start playing that game.
And I'm going to talk a bit more about incentives here. But I think anyone who's been running a business would tell you that whenever you roll out a new initiative, everyone would constantly or subconsciously be thinking, what's in for me? And one of the things I often think about whenever I would make an investment is how does this align with human nature? You know, in this day and age, you know, we see disruption from everywhere, but it's very difficult to disrupt human nature.
And so one of the things that I wanted to highlight is that for 99% of people, it haven't easier time spending other people's money than their own. It sounds so passive aggressive whenever I'm saying this. But like, I think a lot of the AI fears are probably overblown in the sense of how rapid things are going to change. And I'm not questioning at all that AI is going to change a bunch of different things. But I think we sometimes underestimate how much
of these changes that need to be almost brute force and how difficult it is to brute force something in the organization. And it is very difficult to get people to understand something whenever your livelihood is depending on not understanding it. And of course, even that there's a limit to if you don't understand the car and you swore by faster horses, you would eventually have to wake up to the reality. And so I'm not saying that if AI isn't 10 times
better and despite this the switching cost, then we would eventually have to use something else than say Adobe's products. And of course, whenever you ask the CEO about that, he's saying, oh, no, no, no, no, no, AI is not going to disrupt us. It's going to be a tailwind. So we're going to be so much better because of AI. So I don't think that's pretty weak signal. Any CEO that's worth his salt would probably say that today. But I would also be the first to say that
a company like the investors podcast network, we are so dependent on adobe and we're 20 people on the team 15 of them are using adobe. Some of them are just using one app, but most are using the entire suite. And the overall cost is significantly less than 1% of our total cost. So as much as it sounds great, let's use something that's cheaper. And it's sort of like a different discussion if it's better. But let's say that
this is going to be a lot cheaper. You know, even me as one of the owners of the company, as much as I would like to save on cost, it's just not really a cost saver. And whenever you run the company, and of course it depends on the company, but it's not always the greatest people that are paid the most. They are typically one team inside an larger organization. It's the same with CAP. Then you have the salaries to the people that's the biggest cost.
And then the second biggest cost typically the equipment and then a very small part of the cost is the software. So you're looking at something that's very small. So whenever you're doing that, I would say that Adobe is an incredible cheap product for the value that it provides. And I think it's very important that you also whenever you hear people talking about the cost of Adobe, you would have a lot of people who are saying it's ridiculously expensive.
You know, the freelancer who has a side hustle that makes $800 a month. Like, no, like for them to buy the Adobe Suite that's like $70 a month, it's a significant cost. But for a multimillion dollar company, and I'm not necessarily talking about the core coders of the world, but if your turnover is like $5 million and you're spending, I don't know, $3,000 on Adobe Suite, it's not, that's not where you want to skimp on your cost. Especially not if your entire team are trained on
I'm using the software and so I would say that the switching cost is a lot higher than probably what it seems and I also couldn't help myself but to do a bit of scottlbot research and speak to our team members about it. And you could of course also say they would have an all the incentive in the world to tell me that they would never go off adobe but I was speaking with our with our VP from our youtube team and she completely paused whenever I asked her.
What kind of tool would you use if you didn't use Adobe? She had really, really hard time coming up with using something that she could use. And of course you can then use, you know, there are a lot of alternatives. I'm not saying that there aren't alternatives, but right now they just don't have the same functionality. So anyways, I've been rambling here for quite a bit. I wanted to talk a bit more about some of the risks. I wanted to talk about the valuation, but I want to throw it back over here first. Adobe is interesting because it's similar to booking in the sense that
Again, it's AI that is the risk to it. Maybe it never gets easy to weather them. Maybe that's where Adobe really shunts that you can do all of the idea creation and really simple stuff in chat GPT or whatever LLM use. But I think the valuation is very compelling. Stegloch, it's again, there is a big discount in the stock. They're doing a lot of buybacks. If it is sort of temporary or they can adapt or be beneficiaries, then
You're getting a good price. You're getting a good handicap price to take it on here. I think Adobe is very interesting. Let's take a quick break and hear from today's sponsors. One part of being an investor that I don't think gets enough attention is how hard it can be to continue to improve as an investment researcher. And for myself, I often find that when I finish a great conversation with some industry expert or fund manager, my head is full of ideas. But by the time I sit down to write it all up, half of them are already gone.
That's why I've been using Plod Note Pro. It's a small device that sticks to the back of my phone and captures the conversation and hands me back a clean, searchable recap. And so the key points, the follow-ups, the things I usually want to act on, it has all of that. And that allows me to stay present in the room and set a scribbling notes that I won't be able to read back later. And I notoriously have very bad handwriting. And so it's changed how I prep and how I follow up with investors.
It's also built for people who take conversation seriously, enterprise grade security. So if you're recording calls with clients or industry contacts, that's covered too. So if you live in meetings, calls and interviews, we'll give it a look. Go to plod.ai slash wsb and use code WSB for 10% off. That's plod.ai slash WSB code WSB and always get consent before you record a conversation.
They say every day your business is late to AI, you fall two days behind in the competition, they're only moving faster. Fortunately, there's NetSuite Next. You probably already know NetSuite, the AI-powered business suite that securely connects all your data, financials, inventory, commerce, HR, and CRM, all in one source of truth, trusted by over 43,000 customers. NetSuite Next is the next huge leap
because now AI is built into everything you do. It surfaces custom insights throughout your day. AI agents work alongside you on the routine stuff. And anytime you've got a question about anything, you just ask like you're talking to a colleague. And I use it and really I think you should too. For the first time ever, you can try NetSuite Next for free. If your revenue is at least in the seven figures, go to net suite dot AI slash TIP built for every industry, ready for every boardroom.
net suite.ai slash TIP. Curious about online trading but haven't taken the first step yet? You're not alone. And Plus 500 futures is a great place to start. The futures markets are moving fast and with Plus 500 you can explore popular assets like oil, gold, S&P 500, Bitcoin, and more. From crypto to commodities, there's always something happening. The platform is super easy to use so you can trade on the go right from your phone.
You can get started with just $100 and jump into the action. See something interesting? Once your account is open, you can trade it in just a couple of clicks. And if you're not quite ready yet, you can practice with a free demo account. No risk, no pressure. With 20 years of experience, PLUS500 makes trading more accessible than ever. Check it out at PLUS500.com. Trading and futures involves risks of loss and is not suitable for everyone. Not all applicants will qualify. PLUS500.
It's trading with a plus. All right. Back to the show. Yeah, Toby. Thank you so much for your feedback. Of course, I'm biased as I'm saying this, but I'll probably make the argument that to your point about Canva, which is the most obvious competitor, I think the lower end of the market is the one that's most ripe for disruption. And I was speaking with a team member about this. I was the first to say, well, disruption from AI.
She said that it's really the creative control that's where Adobe shines. And she was saying the same thing as you. Like, it can generate things, but as a creative person, you need to tweak things all the time. And that's very difficult to do at least right now with AI. And so I asked her and she was like, Oh, she's using AI within the Adobe suite all the time. And it can do a part of the process. It can't do all of it. Or perhaps it can. They just don't want you to know.
Like so it's you saying, you know, one of the great things is that AI is very good at figuring out like how to clean up this background. Like you can push a button and then it works like you're prompting it, but it works really well with that. But there are so many of the other components where it doesn't do that. So anyways, I found that to be quite compelling. You know, I think especially whenever you look at a stock chart and sort of like to your point, you see how much has been selling off and it just it looks really appealing. They're buying back a lot of shares.
I also think they're issuing too many shares. But I always say that whenever I pitch a stock, that is to some extent the new standard. I think that it is very tricky to think about the valuation. I feel pretty confident that I can underwrite something like 350, 400. And so whenever I was looking into Adobe here and I was thinking, well, perhaps the right time to buy this would be around 200. And again,
trading at 224 just a blink of an eye. And here the past few days is just took a big bump. But anyways, I think one of the challenges that I now see is what they're quite a few, I should probably say. One of them is the top of the funnel. It goes to what you were saying before Toby about Canada. And Canada has been there for quite some time. So take for what it is. But a lot of people get into the Adobe ecosystem very early, whether you are a
created person or not but especially if you create a person and then you continue on that path. You can get it very very cheaply and of course you can say that a subscription for a student is, you know, it's all incremental value is part of the power of the SaaS business model but it's also a way for you to get into the ecosystem so whenever you do work a cooperation whether you're paying for yourself or the company is like what do you want to use well you're going to use Adobe.
But I can see why there might be an issue with top of the funnel where a lot of people are going to say, no, I'm not going to go into Adobe in the first place. Like they have their own top of the funnel product Adobe Express. But with the LMS, like you have some people might never make it to the bottom of the funnel where they really make their money. And so I can't help but make the comparison to the Berkshire Halloway annual shareholders meeting. And you might say, wow, that's a big of a jump here from Adobe.
But one of the things I've been thinking about now has been what's going to happen with the value investing community without Buffett. I was speaking with a mutual friend of ours, Chris Prusun, here the other day about it. And the first thing he said, probably because I articulated myself like extremely important was, hey, I'll continue to go. Of course, I'm going to continue. I have all my friends are there. It's Omaha. You have to go. And that makes a lot of sense. And so in a similar way, if you are a creative person, you work at Hollywood Studio, it has to look really, really good.
Yes, you are on the enterprise, you know, license through Adobe. You're not going to change that and you've done that the past 30 years and you're going to do that in the next 20 years. Like, of course you're going to do that. But what about the top of the funnel? Like, what about, you know, the 26 year old NBA who just doesn't know anyone but like he just wants to go to Omaha and check out the free events and the reason what they really draw is that you just want to see Buffett. That's a big part of the value problem. And now Buffett is no longer there. They just order these.
these private clubs there where people know each other and they've been going for 30 years and why would he go? And I'm not saying it's the most perfect comparison, but whenever I speak to people who have been using Adobe for a number of years, it's the gold standard. That's what they've been taught. That's what everyone used. And if you know your craft, you know the Adobe suite. And so the tools makes a lot of sense. And also they're bundled, right? So
you might be using this app and then you need something else you didn't know that you need it but adobe has that and of course everything works together seems to be just like microsoft office but what if you don't go there in the first place i guess that's my that's my biggest concern and and you might say well you know that doesn't show up in the numbers does it really matter well it matters for the terminal value like what kind of multiple are you are you actually at and i think before the the time of the ellemms
you could underwrite a much, much higher multiple. Like I was mentioning before with Adobe, 96% is a subscription revenue and it's such a sticky product. And so why wouldn't you assign a really, really high multiple? But that's also assuming you still have top of the funnel. What if you don't have that anymore? So whenever I say, oh, it's probably worth 400 bucks, perhaps more, but perhaps not. And so I have a bit of a hard time with the with the evaluation. So anyway,
I want to throw a bag over here to the group and open up any thoughts. It's really an unknowable problem. It's the same problem that we all really have. It's funny that the AI question has become so urgent all of a sudden that it really has impacted so many of these very historically very dominant businesses. As you say, Photoshop is the verb and it's been around for forever. But the content generation
And this is not the editing. The content generation is getting so good on the LLMs that it really is starting. You can see how it could impact these guys down the road. But I still think they're always going to have that. I mean, I don't know. Always, I guess, is along. But that precision editing of those documents is in order to get that precision editing of the LLMs,
you're probably going to need a suite of tools that look something like Adobe anyway. It's a very difficult question to answer. But again, I think you're getting a pretty good discount for the cash flows that it does generate, and it does take longer than everybody thinks for these things to really impact. We may be early adopters, and it may take a lot longer for the bulk of the industry to catch on. It's not uncommon in deep value type scenarios to
have a very long tail where the market thinks that the revenue growth of the earnings fall off almost immediately. In actuality, they're very sticky and it takes years and years and that's that slow decline. It's still a valuable company in slow decline. If it's in that cash cow decline stage of its life cycle, then they're doing the right things. They're buying back stock. It's a great pick and it's one that I've been watching for a long time, but it is a very
interesting time to be investing in the markets. That's so true, Tobi. We talked here before about resulting and coming up with explanations for why things happened. It's a lot more difficult to predict what is actually going to happen. Whenever I look at a company like Adobe, to some extent it also depends on the bit of the state of mind you're in. Sometimes I'm thinking content is abundant.
There's just so much content out there, so much slop. Adobe is needed in a world that's still shifting from physical to digital. And whenever that shift is happening, you need one of Adobe's products to make that happen. And also in the world of a done content, you need the highest quality to separate yourself. It's not a question of making more content. We can all make more content, but it has to be really, really good. And so,
Then you can sort of like talk yourself into saying, you know, the canvas of the world's are going to be disrupted, but the high end really where the money is, they're not going to be disrupted anytime soon because it has to be just right. So it's kind of interesting if you look at the customer groups that Adobe has and they're not breaking out the market-freeze customer group, but you can probably fill in the blanks. They have the 22,000 large enterprise customers and then they have, you know, you can think about them as, you know,
government bodies, Hollywood studios, universities, whatnot. And then they have 41 million paid creator cloud subscribers, such as individuals, freelancers, students, small businesses. And then they have 850 million monthly active free users. And that also includes free acrobat reader users. So it's very wide, quite funneling. They don't pay any money out of that. So you can see where they make the money. I wouldn't be surprised if we would
be talking about this five, ten years from now and say, oh, you know, there were so much pushback from against AI because people want the human element. And of course, XYZ happened or might be the other way around. Like, oh, people just want, you know, want efficiency. And I one of the biases that I experienced is that the experts, the creative people are the best people and the worst people to talk to about Adobe.
They're the best people because they have the most knowledge for farthest reasons. That's why they're experts. But they're also saying people want that human connection. They don't want something that's created by AI. The people who think like that might also be more artistic minded. Whereas some people might be saying, I don't really care if this has been created by AI as part of the process. If I can get it 30% cheaper, then that's fine. Like imagine that you're standing there at the pump and you're like,
I know AI doesn't generate gasoline so to take it for what it is. But if you're like, hey, I can get this for four bucks, I can get this for five bucks. You're like, I just need to drive. And so like, depending on what sort of like where you are and what the product is, I think that is true. Like when it comes to say art, yes, it has to be created by a human couple of sports. Yes, you need to see the athletes. But then there are a ton of other products where that Adobe is probably also touching where you're like, I don't know if people care if AI has been
a big part of the process of creating this digital product or not. So anyways, I'm sure to link to a model of the valuation here of Adobe. I'm going to do the same thing with booking.com and in meta and then people can play around with their own assumptions. But Toby, I know that you also want to chat a bit about building brands from last time that you pitched. Yeah. So building brands has collapsed.
The stock price has collapsed since I pitched it. I can't remember exactly. I think it was at about $27 and it's currently trading a little bit north of $8, which is a very significant breakdown in the stock price. So I thought I should address it. It's basically continued in this drawdown that began 12 months ago. It's had this very significant drawdown from the peak. I think that it is undervalued. It's worth noting that
building brands does carry a reasonable chunk of debt which when they were much bigger market capitalization it's funny because it really doesn't impact the size of the business hasn't changed. If the business has grown slightly over the last 12 months, it's grown less than the market had hoped which is one of the reasons why the stock is down so much but they make these protein ready to drink protein drinks. They are attractive to people who are on the go but the criticism of them has been that they have some.
seed oils in them. They have some soy and folks don't like that. So that has created a problem for them. The market still seems to be consuming. They have grown a little bit, but their growth has slowed materially, which is one of the reasons that the stock's down. You guys know I'm a deep valley guy, so I like big discounts. And I don't mind when a business is struggling a little bit, if you can get enough of a discount in the price to sort of handicap that slow down.
So just to give you some numbers, it still grew year over year, something like 6% year of year, but it has historically grown quite a lot faster than that. So that's the markets now where previously it might have been sort of something that had a reasonable chance of growing quite materially. It was being valued on that basis. The question is now, so there can keep ahead of its inputs on a forward earnings basis. It's a little bit over five times. What has been a pretty good business, although the business does seem to be
deteriorating a little bit on the base of the last print. I think the great risk for it is that it is close to being commoditized product in a very competitive category and there's more competition coming in all the time. You have to weigh that against the fact that there is this general move towards health consciousness as part of that people are consuming more protein. I thought that perhaps it was the GLP ones. So the AI of the health industry is the GLP one.
It's making everybody leaner. I still think it's part of that process. People need to eat more protein. The GOP one sort of stopped you from eating, but once you've reached your goal weight to maintain a healthy body composition, you still need to consume protein. So they do make protein. The question is, for folks who are particularly health conscious, who don't like the seed oils, then these sort of seem to contain them and that seems to be a turn off for many people.
They do continue to make aggressive buybacks. So that says to me that they think that they're undervalued and I tend to think they're undervalued too. I've run a valuation using various different scenarios that it gets you anywhere from $20 at the low end to $70 at the high end. I realize that that's a very wide margin, but I think there is some reasonable uncertainty in that. Just for context with the stock at $8, it's like half of the low end. And so I still think it's pretty good value here. And I mean, to continue to hold it.
The bear thesis is real, but the discount here is so material that I think it's worth holding to see what the next few quarterly reports look like. Very, very appealing. I have to say, with all the red flags and yes, there's always some hair on it. That's why that's the value. Even last time, I was like, wow, that looks interesting. And now, I don't know, I probably got anger at the old price, but it's...
Very interesting pieces. Please continue to provide us with updates, Toby. There has been this sort of general swoon and small and mid-cap stocks. Everything that's impacted by AI or GLP-1 is really can't fight a friend in this market. I do think that I've seen that generally across a lot of the names that I track, that the businesses, if anything, the businesses are inflicting up and starting to do a lot better. But it's coincided with this.
recent rally with the AI stocks. I think the evaluations are now looking, they're really at a decision point where either the market completely runs away from smaller micro or smaller microcatches up soon because I think the forward returns to me look very compelling. They look about as good as they have looked since I've been running the funds. I think that when a lot of the market moves towards one narrative, which is the AI narrative and to some lesser extent specifically for this stock, the GLP1,
Narrative that it does seem to pull money away from the part of the market that hasn't done anything and it creates this little air pocket, which seems to have happened for these stocks. But as I say that that does seem to me to have created pretty good prospects for reasonable forward returns at the same time as these stocks seem to be inflecting out because they have all suffered from an extended period of a pretty weak consumer. This consumer has really been struggling.
from what I can see and with this Iran conflict and higher energy prices, high gas prices that seems to be really putting the bite on people. I think that the time to put these positions on is at the point of maximum pessimism. And we're certainly pessimistic. I hope that it's maximum pessimism. I love it. Famous last words. I love it, Toby. All right. Hari and Toby, thank you so much. It's always great to chat with you.
Let me start over to you guys. What can people learn more about you? Hey, Toby and Stig, always a pleasure to join the mastermind. You can find me on the X or Twitter. My handle is hurry, Rama. I hang out there and I look forward to all your comments, feedback and conversations. And I'm at Greenback on Twitter, GRE and BSEKD. I manage Acquires Funds, which has these ZIG, ETF,
which is mid and large cap deep value and the deep ETF, which is small and micro deep value, the spreads between deep value and the market are extreme at the moment and largely driven by the LLM risks. But a lot of the stocks that are in those are going to be beneficiaries like until the LLMs figure out how to mine and pull energy out of the ground that we're going to be, we're going to need real businesses.
Wonderful. Thank you so much for your time, Jens. It's a privilege as always. Thanks, Stig. Thanks, Harry. Always great. Thank you. Thank you, Toby. Stig, good seeing you both. Thanks for listening to TIP. Follow the Investors Podcast on your favorite podcast app and visit theinvestorspodcast.com for show notes and educational resources. This podcast is for informational and entertainment purposes only and does not provide financial, investment, tax or legal advice.
The content is impersonal and does not consider your objectives, financial situation or needs. Investing involves risk, including possible loss of principle and past performance is not a guarantee of future results. Listeners should do their own research and consult a qualified professional before making any financial decisions. Nothing on this show is a recommendation or solicitation to buy or sell any security or other financial product. Hosts, guests, and the investor's podcast network may hold positions in securities discussed and may change those positions at any time without notice.
References to any third-party products, services or advertisers do not constitute endorsements and the Investors Podcast Network is not responsible for any claims made by them. Copyright by the Investors Podcast Network. All rights reserved.